This is a notebook where you'll be building a characterwise RNN.
在此 notebook 中 我们将构建一个字符级 RNN
You're going to train this on the text of Anna Karenina,
并使用小说《安娜·卡列尼娜》中的文本训练此 RNN
which is a really great but also quite sad a book.
这是一部伟大的小说 但也是个悲剧
The general idea behind this,
我们将
is that we're going to be passing one character at
一次向递归神经网络中
a time into a recurrent neural network.
传入一个字符
We're going to do this for a whole bunch of text,
我们将用一大段文本训练此 RNN
and at the end what's going to happen,
最终
is that our network is going to be able to generate new text,
该网络将能够生成新的文本
one character at a time.
一次生成一个字符
This is the general structure.
基本结构就是这样的
We have our input characters and we want to one-hot encode them.
这是输入字符 我们希望对它们进行独热编码
This one-hot vector, will be fed into a hidden recurrent layer,
然后将此独热编码向量传入隐藏递归层
and then the hidden layer has two outputs.
隐藏层有两个输入
First, it produces some RNN output,
首先生成 RNN 输出
and it produces a hidden state,
并生成隐藏状态
which will continue to change and be fed to
它将继续变化
this hidden layer at the next time step in the sequence.
并在序列的下个时间步传入此隐藏层
We saw something similar in the last code example.
我们在上个代码示例中见过类似情况
So, our recurrent layer keeps track of our hidden state,
递归层会记录隐藏状态
and its output goes to a final fully connected output layer.
输出传入最终全连接输出层
Our linear output layer,
线性输出层
will produce a series of character class scores.
将生成一系列字符类别分数
So, this output will be as long as our input vector,
这个输出将与输入向量一样长
and we can apply a Softmax function to get
我们可以对其应用 Softmax 函数
a probability distribution for the most likely next character.
获得下个概率最高字符的概率分布
So, this network is based off of Andrej Karpathy's post on RNNs, which you can find here.
此网络是基于 Andrej Karpathy 的 RNN 帖子
It's a really good post and so you can check out these links to read more about RNNs.
这是一篇很精彩的帖子 你可以点击这些链接并详细了解 RNN
[inaudible] notebook is broken into a small series of exercises that you can implement yourself.
此 notebook 分成多个小练习 你可以自己完成这些练习
For each exercise, I'm also going to provide a solution to consult.
对于每道练习 我都会提供答案
I recommend that you open the exercise notebook in
建议在一个窗口中打开练习 notebook
one window and watch videos in another.
并在另一个窗口中观看视频
That way you can work alongside me.
这样就可以跟着视频操作
Okay, so first things first,
首先
I'm loading in and taking a look at our text data.
我将加载并查看文本数据
Here, I'm loading in
在这里加载《安娜·卡列尼娜》文本文件
the Anna Karenina text file and I'm printing out the first 100 characters.
并输出前 100 个字符
The characters are everything from letters, to spaces,
这些字符包括字母 空格 换行符等
to newline characters, and we can see the classic first-line,
这是小说的第一行文字
"Happy families are all alike.
“Happy families are all alike;
Every unhappy family is unhappy in its own way."
Every unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.”
Then, I'll actually want to turn our text into numerical tokens.
我希望将文本转换为数字标记
This is because our network can only learn from numerical data,
因为网络只能从数字数据中学习规律
and so we want to map every character in the text to a unique index.
所以我们希望将文本中的每个字符映射到唯一索引
So, first off, with the text,
首先 对于文本
we can just create a unique vocabulary as a set.
我们可以创建唯一词汇表集合
Sets, are a built in python data structure,
集合是内置的 python 数据结构
and what this will do, is look at every character in the past in the text.
它会查看传入文本中的每个字符
Separate it out as a string and get rid of any duplicates.
将文本划分为字符串并删除重复项
So, chars, is going to be a set of all our unique characters.
chars 将是包含所有唯一字符的集合
This is also sometimes referred to as a vocabulary.
有时候称为词汇表
Then, I'm creating a dictionary from a vocabulary of all our characters,
然后根据包含所有字符的词汇表创建字典
that maps the actual character to a unique integer.
将实际字符映射到唯一整数
So, it's just giving a numerical value to each of our unique characters,
即为每个唯一字符设定一个数字值
and putting it in a dictionary int2char.
并放入字典 int2char 中
Then I'm doing this the other way,
然后反过来
where we have a dictionary that goes from integers to characters.
有一个将整数映射到字符的字典
Recall that any dictionary is made of a set of key and value pairs.
字典由键值对组成
In the int2char case,
在 int2char 字典中
the keys are going to be integers and the values are going to be string characters.
键是整数 值是字符串
In the char2int case,
在 char2int 字典中
our keys are going to be the characters and
键是字符
our values are going to be their unique integers.
值是唯一整数
So, these basically give us a way to encode text as numbers.
这样就能够将文本表示为数字
Here, I am doing just that.
在这里
I'm encoding each character in the text as an integer.
将文本中的每个字符表示为整数
This creates an encoded text,
这会生成编码后的文本
and just like I printed the first 100 characters before,
之前输出了前 100 个字符
I can print the first 100 encoded values.
现在也可以输出前 100 个编码值
If you look at the length of our unique characters,
查看唯一字符集的长度
you'll see that we have 83 unique characters in the text.
可以看出文本有 83 个唯一字符
So, our encoded values will fall in this range.
编码值将在此范围内
You can also see some repeating values here like 82,
还有一些重复的值
82, 82 and 19,19.
例如 82 82 82 以及 19 19
If we scroll back up to our actual text,
上拉到实际文本部分
we can surmise that the repeated 82s are probably this new line character,
可以猜测重复的 82 可能表示这个换行符
and 19 is maybe a p. Okay,
19 可能表示 p
so are encodings are working,
编码正确
and now what we want to do,
现在我们希望
is turn these encodings into one-hot vectors,
将这些编码变成独热向量
that our RNN can take in as input,
并能够作为 RNN 的输入
just like in our initial diagram.
和一开始的图表一样
Here, I've actually written a function that takes in an encoded array,
我在这里创建了一个函数
and turns it into a one-hot vector of some specified length.
它会接受编码数组并转换为指定长度的独热向量
I can show you what this does with an example below.
我将在下面用个示例讲解此函数的作用
I've made a short test sequence three, five,
我创建了一个简短的测试序列 [3, 5, 1]
one and a vector length that I specify, eight.
并且将向量长度指定为 8
So, I'm passing this test sequence and the number of
将此测试序列和想要的标签数量
labels that I expect into our one-hot function.
传入独热函数中
I can see that the result is an array of three one-hot vectors.
结果是一个数组 包含 3 个独热向量
All of these vectors are of length eight and the index three,
所有这些向量的长度为 8
five, and one are on for their respective encodings.
在索引 3、5 和 1 处的相应编码已开启
Now, for our vocabulary of 83 characters,
对于有 83 个字符的词汇表
these are just going to be much longer vectors.
这个数组将是长得多的向量
Cool. So, we have our preprocessing functions and data in place,
好的创建好预处理函数和数据后
and now your first task will be to take our encoded characters,
现在的第一个任务是把被编码的字符
and actually turn them into mini batches that we can feed into our network.
变成能传入网络中的迷你批次
So, as Matt mentioned before,
正如 Matt 之前提到的
the idea is that we actually want to run
我们希望一次
multiple sequences through our network at a time.
有多个序列经过网络
Where one mini batch of data contains multiple sequences.
一个迷你批次的数据包含多个序列
So, here's an example starting sequence.
这是一个示例起始序列
If we say we want a batch size of two,
如果我们希望批次大小为 2
we're going to split this data into two batches.
我们将此数据划分为两个批次
Then, we'll have these sequence length windows that
这些是序列长度的窗口
specify how big we want our sequences to be.
指定序列有多大
In this case, we have a sequence length of three,
这里的序列长度是 3
and so our window will be three in width.
所以窗口宽度将是 3
For a batch size of two and sequence length of
对于批次大小 2 和序列长度 3
three these values will make up our first mini-batch.
这些值将构成第一个迷你批次
We'll just slide this window over by three to get the next mini-batch.
使这个窗口滑动 3 个单位 获得下个迷你批次
So, each mini-batch is going to have the dimensions batch size by sequence length.
每个迷你批次的维度将是批次大小 x 序列长度
In this case, we have a two by three window
这里是在传入网络的编码数组上的
on are encoded array that we pass into our network.
2x3 窗口
If you scroll down, I have more specific instructions.
下拉可以看到更多具体说明
The first thing you're going to be doing is taking in an encoded array,
首先接受编码数组
and you'll want to discard any values that don't fit into completely full mini-batches.
并丢弃完整迷你批次多出来的值
Then, you want to reshape this array into batch size number of rows.
然后调整此数组的形状 使其行数为批次大小
Finally, once you have that batch data,
创建批次数据后
you're going to want to create a window that iterates
创建一个窗口
over the batches a sequence length at a time,
每次以序列长度对批次数据进行迭代
to get your mini batches.
以获得迷你批次
So, here's the skeleton code.
这是框架代码
Your array is going to be some encoded data,
数组将是编码数据
then you have a batch size and sequence length.
这是批次大小和序列长度
Basically, you want to create an input x that should be
你需要创建一个输入 x
a sequence length or number of timesteps wide and a batch size tall.
宽为序列长度或时间步数 高为批次大小
This will make up our input data and you'll also want to provide targets.
这样就构成了输入数据 还需要提供目标
The targets y, for this network are going to be just like the input characters x,
此网络的目标 y 和输入字符 x 类似
only shifted over by one.
但是偏移了一个字符
That's because we want our network to predict
因为我们希望网络根据输入序列
the most likely next character more some input sequence.
预测下个最有可能的字符
So, you'll have your input sequence x and our targets y shifted over by one.
所以输入序列是 x  目标y 偏移一位
Then finally, when we [inaudible] batches,
最后 当我们调用 get_batches() 时
we're going to create a generator that iterates through
我们将创建一个生成器
our array and returns x and y with this yield command.
它会遍历数组并使用此 yield 命令返回 x 和 y
Okay, I'll leave implementing this batching function up to you.
现在请你实现这个批次函数
You can find more information about how you could do this in the notebook.
你可以在 notebook 中详细了解如何实现此函数
There's some code for testing out your implementation below.
下面提供了测试实现方法的代码
In fact, this is what your batches should look like when you run this code.
当你运行此代码时 你的批次数据应该看起来这样
If you need any help or you just want to see my solution,
如果需要帮助或想查看我的答案
go ahead and check out the solution video next.
请观看下个 solution 视频